The ingredients you need to make sugar skulls are obviously sugar and I wanted to talk about the kind of sugar you want to use.
You also need something called meringue powder that you can get at bakery stores.
It comes in a couple of different ways.
You can get it in a plastic container like this or sometimes you can get a big bag of it like this, it's the same thing.
Sometimes it comes in a little jar or kind of a little plastic jar.
Basically all it is, is dried egg white mixed with powdered sugar, but it's used as a binding agent for the sugar skulls so that they stay together.
Granulated sugar, meringue powder, and water are the 3 ingredients you need to make the basic composition of the sugar skulls.
A little bit about granulated sugar.
You can get granulated sugar in a lot of different grain sizes and sometimes if you just go get generic granulated sugar it doesn't really say anything about the size of the grains.
So, sometimes that sugar can be kind of course.
I bought extra fine grain, granulated sugar because if you use an extra fine grain it gives a lot more detail to your sugar skulls once you've molded them out.
If you use a courser grain, you can still use it but it looks a little bit coarser. It's up to you.
I prefer a little bit more detail around the eyes and the teeth of my mold.
You see these molds have some fairly fine details in them.
So, I like using a fine grained sugar.
This is an extra fine sugar, that's just my preference.
Meringue powder and water.
Those are the 3 ingredients you need.